<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>technology on Jesstern</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/categories/technology/</link><description>Recent content in technology on Jesstern</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://jsstrn.me/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A simple tool to generate ASCII art</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/notes/generate-ascii-art/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jsstrn.me/notes/generate-ascii-art/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a simple tool to generate ASCII art.</description></item><item><title>Assign a .local domain to your Synology NAS</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/notes/synology-local-domain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jsstrn.me/notes/synology-local-domain/</guid><description>Using an IP address can be quite cumbersome, so let&amp;rsquo;s assign a .local domain to your NAS.
Head over to Control Panel and select Network. Under the General tab, set your server name. Click Apply and you can now access your NAS with http://&amp;lt;server-name&amp;gt;.local:5000 from a web browser that&amp;rsquo;s within the same local network.</description></item><item><title>Backup your data with Hyper Backup on Synology NAS</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/notes/synology-backup-your-data-with-hyper-backup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jsstrn.me/notes/synology-backup-your-data-with-hyper-backup/</guid><description>Install the Hyper Backup package in your Synology NAS and configure it to back up your data on an external cloud service such as S3, Dropbox, etc.</description></item><item><title>Buying a Raspberry Pi</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/notes/raspi-purchase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jsstrn.me/notes/raspi-purchase/</guid><description>Tips on how to buy your first Raspberry Pi</description></item><item><title>Check the architecture of your Synology NAS</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/notes/synology-cpu-architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jsstrn.me/notes/synology-cpu-architecture/</guid><description>It may be useful for troubleshooting to know the architecture and CPU of your Synology NAS server.
For instance, the Synology DS218j model is an x18 Series and has a Dual Core Marvell Armada 385 88F6820 with 512MB of DDR3 RAM.</description></item><item><title>Connect to your Synology NAS from a web browser</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/notes/synology-connect-via-browser/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jsstrn.me/notes/synology-connect-via-browser/</guid><description>First, check that your NAS server and your computer are on the same network.
You can connect to your NAS server by pointing your browser to http://&amp;lt;your-ip-address&amp;gt;:5000 and then provide the login credentials.
Check your home router to determine what IP address has been assigned to your NAS server. Optionally, you can fix an IP address so its easier for you to connect to your NAS in future.
If you have set up a .</description></item><item><title>Connect to your Synology NAS with SSH</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/notes/synology-connect-via-ssh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jsstrn.me/notes/synology-connect-via-ssh/</guid><description>First, open Control Panel and navigate to Terminal &amp;amp; SNMP. Next, enable SSH service. Click Apply. Now you can SSH into your NAS with your credentials.
Open a terminal and connect to your NAS server via SSH
ssh &amp;lt;user&amp;gt;@&amp;lt;ip-address&amp;gt; If you have set up a .local domain, then
ssh &amp;lt;user&amp;gt;@&amp;lt;server-name&amp;gt;.local You will be prompted for your password.</description></item><item><title>Consolidate all your cloud storage data with Cloud Sync</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/notes/synology-sync-cloud-data-with-cloud-sync/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jsstrn.me/notes/synology-sync-cloud-data-with-cloud-sync/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s not uncommon to have our data stored on multiple sources on the cloud. We might have some data stored on Dropbox, others on Google Drive, and still others on iCloud Drive.
With Synology&amp;rsquo;s Cloud Sync, they can finally all live in one place.</description></item><item><title>Create a resume with JSON Resume</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/notes/create-resume-with-json/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jsstrn.me/notes/create-resume-with-json/</guid><description>Install resume-cli tool
npm install -g resume-cli Create a new resume.json file
resume init Validate resume.json to ensure it adheres to the schema
resume validate Export your resume to HTML or PDF with themes
resume export --format &amp;lt;type&amp;gt; --theme &amp;lt;theme-name&amp;gt; Serve your resume.json locally
resume serve --theme &amp;lt;theme-name&amp;gt; To host your resume online, create a Gist on GitHub named resume.json and point to http://registry.jsonresume.org/&amp;lt;your-github-username&amp;gt;.</description></item><item><title>How to download online videos</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/notes/download-online-videos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jsstrn.me/notes/download-online-videos/</guid><description>Download the youtube-dl command line tool from brew
brew install youtube-dl youtube-dl supports a huge list of extractors, including popular sites like YouTube and Vimeo.
List all extractors and pipe it into grep to search for an extractor
youtube-dl --list-extractors | grep &amp;#34;udemy&amp;#34; To download a video
youtube-dl &amp;#34;video-url&amp;#34; Simply pass in the cookie file to download videos that require login credentials
youtube-dl --cookies &amp;lt;path-to-cookie-file&amp;gt; &amp;#34;video-url&amp;#34; You can use a browser extension like cookie.</description></item><item><title>Keep your Synology NAS updated</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/notes/synology-update-packages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jsstrn.me/notes/synology-update-packages/</guid><description>Update your packages It&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to periodically check that all your packages are updated. Head over to Package Manager, select Installed and update any packages as required.
You can also set up automatic updates from the settings within Package Manager and verify that Update packages automatically has been checked.
Update DiskStation Manager (DSM) Open the Control Panel and navigate or search for Update &amp;amp; Restore. Next, update your DSM as required.</description></item><item><title>Setup a home media server with Video Station on Synology NAS</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/notes/synology-setup-media-server-with-video-station/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jsstrn.me/notes/synology-setup-media-server-with-video-station/</guid><description>Setup a home media server with Synology&amp;rsquo;s Video Station.
Download DS Video to watch your videos on Apple TV and iOS.</description></item><item><title>Setup a local web server with a Synology NAS</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/notes/synology-setup-web-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jsstrn.me/notes/synology-setup-web-server/</guid><description>Go to Package Center and install Web Station. Now you should be able to see a default webpage when you visit http://&amp;lt;your-ip-address&amp;gt; or http://&amp;lt;server-name&amp;gt;.local (the default port is 80).
To edit the webpage, go to the web directory in your File Station.
Note that the website is only accessible within your local network. If you want to be access it via the internet you&amp;rsquo;ll need to setup DDNS.</description></item><item><title>Setup Plex media server on your Synology NAS</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/notes/synology-setup-plex-media-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jsstrn.me/notes/synology-setup-plex-media-server/</guid><description>Plex is no longer listed as a third-party package on Package Manager for DSM 7.0 and the one that is listed for DSM 6.2 is outdated, so you have to manually install the media server.
Download Plex media server for Synology and manually install the package with Package Manager.
If you&amp;rsquo;re on DSM 7.0 you might not be able to find Plex media server in the Package Center, you can either manually install it or try Emby as an alternative.</description></item><item><title>Which mechanical keyboard switch should I choose?</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/notes/mechanical-keyboards/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jsstrn.me/notes/mechanical-keyboards/</guid><description>Choosing between the different types of mechanical keyboard switches?</description></item></channel></rss>