<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>vscode on Jesstern</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/tags/vscode/</link><description>Recent content in vscode on Jesstern</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://jsstrn.me/tags/vscode/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Install VSCodium instead of VS Code</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/notes/vscode-install-vscodium/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jsstrn.me/notes/vscode-install-vscodium/</guid><description>By default, VS Code will send diagnostic data which you disable in settings. To do this, search for telemetry in settings and select off under Telemetry Level.
Another approach is to install VSCodium which contains the original open sourced binaries and has telemetry disabled by default.
For macOS, use Homebrew to install VSCodium
brew install vscodium</description></item><item><title>Learn to use VS Code more efficiently</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/notes/vscode-learn-to-use-more-efficiently/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jsstrn.me/notes/vscode-learn-to-use-more-efficiently/</guid><description>Multi-cursor editing Select your text, hit Shift-Command-L to select all occurences of the selection. Command-D to select them one at a time.
Add a new cursor above or below, Option-Command + up/down arrow keys.
Hit Escape key to exit multi-cursor mode.
IntelliSense The default shortcut key to trigger suggestions is Control-Space or Fn-Control-Space. If this does not work, try the Option-Escape keys.
Line actions To delete an entire line, hit Shift-Command-K or Command-X.</description></item><item><title>Limit number of open editors in VS Code</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/notes/vscode-set-editor-limit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jsstrn.me/notes/vscode-set-editor-limit/</guid><description>We can limit the number of open editors in VS Code by configuring the following in settings:
workbench.editor.limit.enabled: true – enable editor limit; default is false workbench.editor.limit.value: 1 – set number of open editors; default is 10 workbench.editor.limit.perEditorGroup: true – allow side-by-side panels; default is false</description></item></channel></rss>