<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Blogs on Jesstern</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Jesstern</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 16:09:10 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jsstrn.me/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Do not send sensitive data via email</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/blog/security-do-not-send-sensitive-data-via-email/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 16:09:10 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://jsstrn.me/blog/security-do-not-send-sensitive-data-via-email/</guid><description>Sending sensitive data via email is a bad idea for several reasons.
We might be inclined to think that we can first encrypt our documents before sending them, but we soon realize that we have another problem – how do we send the password to our recipient?
Of course, we can&amp;rsquo;t send the password via email. What some companies have done is to use a password that is known to the customer, like their date of birth or account number and even include the format for the password.</description></item><item><title>Singapore's approach to taxation</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/blog/singapore-approach-to-taxation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 20:07:04 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://jsstrn.me/blog/singapore-approach-to-taxation/</guid><description>Several years ago, a friend of mine from Germany visited Singapore. They were really impressed with the well maintained roads, excellent public transportation system, and infrastructure. However, they wondered how it was possible for the Singapore government to fund all this with such low income taxes.
In countries like Germany and Australia, they have very high income taxes in order to pay for public goods such as healthcare, education, transportation, and infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>The problem with inflammatory foods</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/blog/health-problem-with-inflammatory-foods/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 12:19:40 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://jsstrn.me/blog/health-problem-with-inflammatory-foods/</guid><description>Over 2000 years ago, Hippocrates, widely considered the father of medicine, believed that &amp;ldquo;all disease begins in the gut&amp;rdquo;. It would seem he was on to something.
In 2020, I kept a log of the food I ate and the effects its had on my digestive system. From this observation, I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to identify several foods that I&amp;rsquo;m sensitive to. I decided to remove gluten from my diet for a month to see the effects it would have.</description></item><item><title>The etymology of 'thou' and 'you'</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/blog/etymology-thou-you/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 21:56:36 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://jsstrn.me/blog/etymology-thou-you/</guid><description>When we were children, we might have been taught this in English grammar class:
He is happy She is happy I am happy You are happy Why is it that we say, &amp;ldquo;you are happy,&amp;rdquo; rather than, &amp;ldquo;you is happy,&amp;rdquo; even though &amp;lsquo;you&amp;rsquo; is singular? The answer can be found in its etymology.
In the past, we used to use the word &amp;lsquo;thou&amp;rsquo; as the second person singular form while &amp;lsquo;you&amp;rsquo; was actually the plural form used to refer to two or more people.</description></item><item><title>Secrets to looking younger than your age</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/blog/secrets-to-looking-younger-than-your-age/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 14:05:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://jsstrn.me/blog/secrets-to-looking-younger-than-your-age/</guid><description>When the founder of Telegram turned 36, he wrote about his secrets to looking younger than his age.
Pavel Durov listed seven tips – avoid alcohol, sleep more, avoid overeating, exercise regularly, limit stress, avoid eating meat, and live alone.
Of these seven, I follow all of them except for living alone. I also avoid caffeine.</description></item><item><title>Beware the lame JavaScript interview question</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/blog/js-lame-interview-question/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 01:21:42 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://jsstrn.me/blog/js-lame-interview-question/</guid><description>This question is from Interview Cake.
var text = &amp;#39;outside&amp;#39; function displayText() { console.log(text) var text = &amp;#39;inside&amp;#39; } displayText() What do you think will be output onto the console?
It&amp;rsquo;s not &amp;ldquo;outside&amp;rdquo;.
It&amp;rsquo;s not &amp;ldquo;inside&amp;rdquo; either.
It&amp;rsquo;s actually &amp;ldquo;undefined&amp;rdquo; because of the hoisted variable.
The question is trying to test your understanding on variable hoisting when using the var keyword, but we should not even be using var in modern JavaScript in the first place.</description></item></channel></rss>