<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>general on Jesstern</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/categories/general/</link><description>Recent content in general on Jesstern</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 20:07:04 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jsstrn.me/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Singapore's approach to taxation</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/blog/singapore-approach-to-taxation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 20:07:04 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://jsstrn.me/blog/singapore-approach-to-taxation/</guid><description>Several years ago, a friend of mine from Germany visited Singapore. They were really impressed with the well maintained roads, excellent public transportation system, and infrastructure. However, they wondered how it was possible for the Singapore government to fund all this with such low income taxes.
In countries like Germany and Australia, they have very high income taxes in order to pay for public goods such as healthcare, education, transportation, and infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>List of foods to avoid</title><link>https://jsstrn.me/notes/list-of-foods-to-avoid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jsstrn.me/notes/list-of-foods-to-avoid/</guid><description>After tracking my food intake for over a year and monitoring any side effects that I would feel after eating, I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered that I should avoid foods that contain lactose, capsaicin, gluten, alcohol, and caffeine (ranked by order of most severe reaction to least severe reaction).
Lactose Milk Cheese Butter Ice-cream Cake Cream Pancake Yoghurt Capsaicin Chili Curry Gluten Wheat Rye Buckwheat Bread Noodles Ramen Udon Pasta Pancake Waffle Cereal Muesli Granola Cake Beer Alcohol Beer Cider Spirits Wine Caffeine Coffee Green tea Black tea Chocolate</description></item></channel></rss>